Coolidge, John, 1913-1995. Papers, 1939-1984: A Guide
Papers, 1939-1984
- Personal Papers, III.
  - Personal Correspondence, A.
    - Loring Wolcott[1968], 115.
      [Note: High risk confidential information expunged and original RESTRICTED; access requires the written permission of the Curator of the Harvard Art Museum Archives]
    - John Coolidge Personal [1967-1968], 116-117.
      [Note: Some materials in folder 116 are RESTRICTED; access requires the written permission of the Curator of the Harvard Art Museum Archives]
    - John Coolidge 1967-68 [1967-1968], 118.
    - Harvard Records - J.C. [1947-1968], 119-121.
    - Personal [1946, 1962, 1968], 122.
    - J.C. Projects [1968, n.d.], 123.
    - Loring Wolcott[1966-1967], 124.
    - J.C.'s Trip to Turkey & Israel -- July - Aug. 4, 1966 [1966-1967], 125-126.
    - 67 Trip to Europe, Taxes [1965-1967], 127.
    - John Coolidge - 1966-1967 [1958-1959, 1965-1967], 128.
    - John Coolidge - Academic Record, Publications, Memberships [1947-1967], 129.
    - John Coolidge - Personal 1965-66 [1963, 1965-1966], 130.
    - John Coolidge - Personal 1964-65 [1946, 1964-1965], 131.
    - J.C.s Photographs and Negatives[1957-1965, n.d.], 132-134.
    - John Coolidge - Personal 1963 [1963-1964], 135.
    - J.C. Personal 1962-1963, 136.
    - 1961-62 J.C. - Personal [1961-1962], 137.
    - J.C. Personal 1960-1961, 138.
    - J.C. Personal 1959-1960, 139.
    - J.C. Personal 1958-1959 [1943, 1957-1959], 140.
    - J.C. Personal 1957-1958 [1953-1958], 141-142.
    - J.C. Retirement Plan [1950-1958], 143.
    - Coolidge - Personal 1955-1957 [1954-1957], 144-146.
    - German Trip, Oct. 17 - Nov. 17, 1954, 147.
    - Coolidge - Personal 1953-1954, 148-149.
      [Note: item removed from folder 148 to oversize cabinet]
    - Coolidge - Personal 1952-1953, 150-151.
    - John Coolidge - Personal 1951-1952, 152.
    - J.C. Golden Wedding January 1951, 153.
    - John Coolidge - Personal 1950-1951, 154-155.
    - Coolidge - Blue Cross Blue Shield [policy brochures and membership card] [1949-1951?], 156.
    - Pers. Coolidge, John 1949-July 1, 1950 [1949-1950], 157.
    - Coolidge - Italy [1949], 158.
    - Coolidge: Personal 1948-1949, 159.
    - Coolidge: Personal 1947-1948, 160.
    - Office [furniture brochures] [n.d.], 161.
  - Fogg, B.
    - Mongan - Barr et al. [Lecture by Agnes Mongan and account of Soviet Union by Seymour Slive][1983-1984], 162.
    - Shahnahme [Correspondence regarding the publication of the Dickson and Welch catalogue] [1969-1970], 163.
    - Letters Accepting or Regretting J.C. Party, May 27, 1968, 164-170.
  - Writings, C.
    - Introduction [and notes regarding Boston development] [n.d.], 171.
    - Edward Forbes [draft foreword for 1971 memorial exhibition catalogue] [1971?], 172.
    - Mrs. J. [Jesse] Straus [correspondence and foreword for sale catalog] [1970], 173.
    - Mill and Mansion
      - [Mill and Mansion --] Mill and Mansion [1943-1946], 174.
      - [Mill and Mansion --] Lowell [, MA] Correspondence [1939-1942], 175-177.
        [Note: Some materials in folder 176 are RESTRICTED; access requires the written permission of the Curator of the Harvard Art Museum Archives]
      - [Mill and Mansion --] KHFTS [?] [1941], 178.
      - Mill and Mansion - Fan Mail [1942-1943], 179.
  - Organizations, D.
    - AAMD [Association of Art Museum Directors] Ethics [Notes, draft and report] [1971], 180.
    - Felix's [Preservation of historic storefront in Harvard Square] [1967-1971], 181.
    - Felix [Preservation of historic storefront in Harvard Square] [1970], 182.
    - [untitled] [Primarily copies of clipping regarding education, the arts and museums] [1970, n.d.], 183.
    - B. V. [?] American Art [n.d.], 184.
    - New Art History [New Art Association][1970], 185.
    - WM. Rubin, Foundation Trustee [1966], 186.
    - SAH [Society of Architectural Historians] Session Jan. 1966 [1965-1966], 187-188.
    - Soc. Of Arch. Historians[1961, 1964-1966], 189-190.
    - Art Hist. Dining Club[1964-1966], 191-192.
    - Invitations, Announcements, etc. [1953, 1960-1965], 193.
    - 25th Reunion [Report on University Activities] [1960], 194.
    - J.C. 20th Reunion, 1955 [1953-1955], 195-198.
      [Note: item removed from folder 195 to oversize cabinet]
    - J.C. Collectors Dining Club[1948-1951], 199.
  - Projects, E.
    - Daedalus [Journal of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences] - Museums [1971], 200-201.
    - Harvard and Acquisitions [1970-1971], 202.
    - [Jules] Prown - Mellon [Center for British Art at Yale University][1967-1970?], 203-204.
    - Old Cambridge [Notes and drafts regarding] [n.d.], 205.
    - [Institute in] Arts Administration [at Harvard Summer School] [1970?], 206.
Box and Folder Locations
Box 1: Folders 1-31
Box 2: Folders 32-52
Box 3: Folders 53-74
Box 4: Folders 75-103
Box 5: Folders 104-119
Box 6: Folders 120-136
Box 7: Folders 137-152
Box 8: Folders 153-177
Box 9: Folders 178-197
½ Box 10: Folders 198-206
Box 11: Closed and Restricted Materials
Oversize Cabinet: Oversize Materials
Catalog Entries:
The following catalog entries represent persons, organizations, and topics documented in this collection. An entry for each appears in the Harvard On Line Library Information System (HOLLIS) and other automated bibliographic databases. THIS IS NOT AN INDEX
Names and Subjects
American Association of Museums
Art and Architecture
Art Dealers--United States
Art Galleries, Commercial
Art Historians
Art Historians--Massachusetts--Cambridge
Art in Universities and Colleges
Art Museum Directors
Art Museums--Administration
Art Museums--Educational Aspects
Art Objects--Collectors and Collecting
Art Objects--Private Collections
Art Patrons
Art Publishing
Art--Attribution
Art--Collectors and Collecting--United States
Art--Criticism and Interpretation
Art--Exhibition Techniques
Art--Exhibitions
Art--History--Study and Teaching (Higher)--United States
Art--Private Collections
Arts Administrators--United States
Art--Societies, etc.
Art--Study and Teaching--Massachusetts
Art--Study and Teaching--United States
Cambridge (Mass.)
Class Reunions
Collectors and Collecting
College Art Museums--Massachusetts--Cambridge
Coolidge, John, 1913-1995
Curriculum Planning
Deknatel, Frederick B.
Exhibitions
Fogg Art Museum
Fogg Art Museum--Administration
Fogg Art Museum--Benefactors
Fogg Art Museum--History
Harvard Art Museum
Harvard University. Dept. of Fine Arts
Harvard University. Dept. of History of Art & Architecture
Harvard University--Alumni and Alumnae
Harvard University--Benefactors
Harvard University--Curricula
Harvard University--Faculty
Harvard University--Museums
Harvard University--Students
Hofer, Philip, 1898-1984
Krautheimer, Richard, 1897-1994
Kuhn, Charles Louis
Lectures and Lecturing
Museology
Museum Architecture
Museum Directors
Museum Directors--Massachusetts
Museum Exhibits
Museum of Fine Arts, Boston
Museum of Fine Arts, Boston. Trustees
Museum Techniques--Study and Teaching (Higher)--United States
Museums--Administration
Museums--Employees--Training of
Museums--Massachusetts
Object--Teaching
Prown, Jules David
Rathbone, Perry Townsend, 1911-
Rosenberg, Jakob, 1893-
Sachs, Paul J. (Paul Joseph), 1878-1965
Slive, Seymour, 1920-
Society of Architectural Historians
Yale Center for British Art
Form/Genre Terms
Announcements
Brochures
Contract(s)
Curricula
Exhibition records
Financial records
Floor plans
Form letters
Galley proofs
Insurance records
Invitations
Itineraries
Lecture note(s)
Lecture(s)
Letters of advice
Letters of recommendation
Memorandums
Minutes
Museum records
Negative(s)
Outlines (documents)
Photograph(s)
Postcards
Report(s)
Resume(s)
School records
Speeches
Syllabi
Term papers
Traffic tickets